Adriano DALPANE

+39 351 77 64 234 – <u>adriano.dalpane@gmail.com</u> **Age:** 39 - **Nationality**: Italian - **Location**: Brescia, Italy

PROFILE

Senior Developer, 12 years of experience, last 3 of which using Rust. Autonomous, values neat code writing and working in small teams.

Fluent in English and French, native Italian speaker.

Can work on B2B contract by invoicing.

Requires 1 month of notice period to guit current occupation.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/adriano-dalpane https://github.com/digitalillusion https://deverse.xyz

EXPERIENCE

knobs.it

Jul 2023 - now

Rust developer

Developed a notarization system over blockchain for an intelligent trash-bin network of an environmental operator, featuring import of the data, the visualization and search of entries, and the verification whether required. Neon, Polygon blockchain, Prisma, mysql, Azure functions, Delta Sharing Deployed smart contracts on Radix: a fork of a money market featuring, supply, redeem, collateralized borrow, and liquidation.

Radix, Scrypto, Supra Oracle

Rewrite to Rust of an existing backend featuring transaction notarization and user operation bundling for an application that allows account abstraction.

Ethereum, Polygon blockchain, Kafka, redis, Prisma, mongodb, axum, serde

Implementation of a prototype for a volunteering and donations application over Internet Computer decentralized platform. Featuring price oracle integration, HTTP initialization of the canister and persistent data storage. Internet Computer, XRC, internet identity

Worked on an NFT marketplace backend written in Rust. Refactored the codebase to maximize performances and maintainability. Asyncronous programming, integration tests with mock layer.

Ethereum, Linea blockchain, GraphQL, IPFS, mongodb, redis, axum, swagger, serde

Anagolay network

Nov 2021 – Feb 2023

Rust developer

Implementation of a framework that allows reproducible execution of immutable code in workflows, under WASM or Rust; deployed on a polkadot parachain that deal with IP management. Developed pallets with custom types, genesis, off-chain worker, RPC APIs, benchmarks and unit tests. Migrated standalone node to parachain template. Contributed to development of middleware and frontend to support an homemade SDK.

Substrate, WASM, IPFS, postgresql, nodejs, typescript, svelte, scale codec

Master The Monster Java developer

Sep 2020 - Nov 2021 Worked on a platform for video content production and marketplace

> between brands and producers. Implemented a Bayesian classifier to perform match making. Contributed to some frontend development Spring Boot, cassandra, angularis, typescript, swagger, Stripe APIs

Freelance projects

Created a tool to synchronize an online shop inventory from an excel file Mar 2020 – Sep 2020 toward Woocommerce and ebay

Spring Boot, kotlin, postgresql, ReactJs, woocommerce REST APIs

Created point-and-click RTS game using Godot engine and Monte Carlo Tree Search artificial intelligence that compiles to WASM and runs in

browser

gdnative, Rust, WASM

Created an utility to upgrade an UDP connection to be reliable using

Aeron driver Aeron, Rust Portfolio website

Typescript, GatsbyJS, GraphQL, ReactJS

Monaco Telecom Java developer

May 2016 – Feb 2020 Worked on service bus, network interface, provisioning and inventory

utility of different telecom operators. Contributed to migration of old

backends toward microservices architecture.

Spring Boot, postgresgl, Neo4J, Keycloak, rabbitmg, Kafka, Apache

Camel

Amadeus SAS Java developer

Sep 2012 – May 2016 Worked on the booking engine and APIs of a major player

> in the travel industry Webservices, swagger

EDUCATION

2018 Coursera Course Certificates, Machine Learning

2016 Oracle Certification Program, Java 8 Programmer II

2011 Master Degree in Computer Science - Politecnico di Milano, Italy

CONTRIBUTIONS

https://github.com/r3stl355/delta-sharing-rust-client Rust Client that integrate with Delta Sharing.